He came to visit me sometimes...until recently.
時々 来てくれますよ その前まで…
Long time no see, Kida Masaomi.
久しぶりだね 紀田正臣君
What is this?!
なんだ こりゃあ!?
They disappeared after an altercation with another gang.
他のチームとの 抗争がきっかけで姿を消したんですけどね～
And you can't just go ask Orihara Izaya, can you?
まさか折原臨也に聞くわけにいかないもんねぇ
You dragged me back into this...
オレを引き戻しやがって ちくしょう…
Damn it.
Damn it!
ちくしょう！
So, your friend was hospitalized?
友達が入院したんだって？
Who'd you hear that from?
誰に聞いた？
I saw it from my window.
窓から見えたよ 毎日 来てたもんね
You came to visit every day.
So, your friend's a girl, right?
やっぱり 女の子？
She has a nice body and wears glasses; that lack
of balance makes her an attractive high schooler.
ナイスバディで眼鏡
アンバランスさが魅力の女子高生さ
Do you like her?
好きなの？
Yeah. I'm smack dab in the middle of
a love triangle involving her and my friend.
ああ 親友と三角関係の真っ最中だよ
It'd be a love square if you included me.
私も入れれば四角関係だよ
We're done, finished, canceled, closed up.
オレたちはもう終わった フィニッシュ
打ち切り 店じまい
Right?
そうだろ？
Then why do you keep visiting me?
なら どうして来てくれるの？
Have you decided you want to return to how things were?
また 昔に戻りたくなったとか？
Sorry, I'm going home.
悪い 今日はもう帰るわ
You'll come back, Masaomi.
正臣は戻ってくるよ
I mean, you always do.
だって それは決まってることだもん
So I'm fine no matter how many girls you fall in love with.
だから いくら ほかの女の子を好きになっても 平気
In the end, you'll show a much stronger
love toward me than any of them.
最後の最後に 正臣はその子たちより 私の方を強く愛してくれるんだから
I didn't have to listen to know what she was going to say.
聞かなくたって 分かってる
She always repeats the same thing;
同じことの繰り返しだ
that I'll return to her no matter how many girls I date.
「たくさんの女の子とつきあっても」
「きっと 私のところに戻ってくる」
And, more so than any of them, you'll love me on a much higher level.
そしたら そのほかの人との愛より もっともっと 高く高く 愛してくれるもん
However, I didn't want to hear the words that would come next.
でも それから先の言葉は聞きたくなかった
I mean, that's what Izaya said.
だって 臨也さんがそう言ってたもん
I succumb to the illusion that I'm God when I look
at it like this, which feels pretty good, you know.
こうやって見てるとさ
自分が神様だっていう錯覚に陥って
なかなか気持ちいいもんだよ
Three-way fights are great.
三つ巴って いいね
Moreover, all three leaders are friends with each other.
しかも リーダー同士が密接にくっついてる
God attack!
神様アタ～ック！
The sweeter the honeymoon, the higher the flames
of despair rise when it all comes crashing down.
蜜月が濃ければ濃いほど それが崩れたときの絶望は高く高く 燃え上がるもんだよ
Look! The pawns are like garbage!
見ろ！ 駒がゴミのようだ
Now, what do the cards say about the non-pawns?
さてと… あとはそれぞれ駒以外のカードがどう動くかだよねぇ
Kadota's group, Shinra, Simon...
門田たちに 新羅 サイモン
Umm...I guess Shizu-chan's the king after all.
えっと… キングは シズちゃんかな
Celty's the queen, I suppose.
やっぱ セルティはクイーンだな
Then who's the joker...
じゃあ ジョーカーは…
Meh, whatever.
まあ どうでもいいわ
This has gotten fun, hasn't it?
楽しくなってきたよね
You think so too, right?
君もそう思うだろ？
I heard that she didn't die.
死ななかったんだって？
How fortunate.
僥倖じゃないか
It'll all work out as long as she's alive.
生きてさえいれば なんとでもなる
Izaya...
臨也さん…
You're pretty smart;
君は 頭がいいねぇ
you understand that you're the reason she ended up like that.
彼女があんな状態になった原因が自分にあると 分かってる
It's laudable that you haven't succumbed
to your emotions and tried to punch me—
感情にのまれて オレに殴りかかってこなかったことは称賛に値するよ
Bingo.
正解
It's only natural that you'd channel your anger towards me.
今のはオレに怒りを向けて 当然だ
Since I was obviously trying to insult you.
明らかに悪意を持って 君をからかったわけだから
So, she's unconscious?
意識不明か？
I hope she wakes up.
目を覚ますといいね
Or maybe you hope that she'll never come out of it.
それとも 君にとっては永遠に目を覚ましてくれない方が いいのかな？
What are you trying to say...?!
どういう意味っすか？
You know....
分かってるくせに
You're scared, aren't you?
君は怖いんだろ？
You figure that if she wakes up,
she'll blame you for the rest of your life.
彼女が目を覚ましたら 永遠に責められ続けるんじゃないかって
But, let's assume that she dies.
だけど 仮に このまま死んだとしたら どうだろう？
Wouldn't you feel guilty for the rest of your life that you killed her?
それこそ 一生償えない罪悪感にまみれて 生きることになる？
In other words, your feelings of guilt are
meaningless whether she lives or dies.
つまり 彼女が生きようが死のうが
君の罪悪感にはなんの意味もないよ
You can't run away.
逃げられないって
The past will be only too happy to chase you—
過去ってやつは お構いなしに君のことを追い回す
In absolute, complete, and total earnest.
ひたすら ひたすら ひたすら ひたすら…
Do you know why?
なんでだか分かるかい？
Because it's lonely.
さみしいからさ
The past and memories get lonely easily.
過去や思い出ってやつは とてもさみしがり屋でね
I don't believe in God.
オレはね 神様って信じてないんだよ
Because he doesn't have a fixed form.
存在が確定してないからね
The past certainly does exist, even in a world
where the future doesn't have a fixed form.
未来でさえ確定してない世の中で
過去は確かに存在している
Even if it's been colored by misunderstandings and delusions,
たとえ それが誤解や妄想に彩られたことだとしても
a person's past can't be anything but
the truth as long as he believes in it.
本人がそれを信じるなら
過去は確かに真実にほかならない
If that's what you base your actions...or your way of life on,
それに基づいて行動を… あるいは生きざまを決めるというのなら
isn't that like being a deity?
それは 確かに神の一種なんじゃないのかな
I don't understand what you're trying to say at all!
何が言いたいのかさっぱり分かりません！
Yeah, you do...
分かってるくせに
You can't run from her anymore.
君はもう彼女から逃げられないよ
Your feelings of guilt towards her will become
your past, and she'll become a deity to you.
彼女への罪悪感は過去となり
彼女は君にとっての神になる
Well, that should be fine, right?
まあ いいんじゃないの？
Since you like her...
彼女のこと好きなんだからさ
I see you've recovered wonderfully, Anri!
杏里も見事に復活だな よかったよ
That's great; Anri and her eros are safe!
杏里も 杏里のエロも 無事で
"Eros" is going too far, Masaomi.
エロは余計だよ 正臣
But I'm really glad you're okay. I really am.
でも 本当によかった 本当にね…
Uh, umm...thanks, you two.
あの… ありがとう 二人とも
You don't have to thank me.
お礼なんて やめてくれよ
I'm happy as long as you and your eros are okay!
オレは 杏里と杏里のエロが無事なら それで満足なんだからさ
The same for me—except for the eros thing.
僕も エロ以外は同じだよ
Hello?
もしもし
I see.
そう 分かった
Got it.
I'll be right there.
そんじゃ すぐ行くわ
Sorry! Something just came up with my friend!
悪い！ 友達がなんか急用あるっつうからさ
Oh, really?
あっ そうなの？
If you want to hate someone, hate my friend to your heart's content!
恨むなら オレの友達を好きなだけ恨んでくれ
Hate doesn't cost anything, and it doesn't cause me any harm!
恨むなら タダだし オレには被害がない
It's a perfect "two birds with one
stone," it's "many wives for one man!"
まさに 一石二鳥 一夫多妻だからな！
"Many wives for one man?"
一夫多妻？
See you tomorrow!
じゃあ また明日な～～！
I wonder if it's really that important?
そんなに急ぎの用事なのかな？
Don't you think Kida's been acting strange lately?
紀田君 最近 ちょっと様子がおかしいと思いませんか？
Really?
そうかな 気のせいじゃない？
You're sure it's not all in your head?
I've never told Mikado about my
involvement in the Yellow Scarves.
黄巾賊の話を帝人にしたことはなかった
Where he is and this place are both realities to me...
あいつのいる場所と ここと
どちらの現実も オレにとっては現実なのに
But I feel like an incredible distance separates them...
そこには ひどく 距離があるような気がして…
We fought every day.
ケンカ ケンカの毎日だった
We'd stay connected to each other only if we continued to fight.
それを続けることでしか つながっていない仲間たちだった
I wanted someone to affirm my existence.
自分を肯定してくれる 誰かが欲しかった
It was then...that I first met Saki.
そのころだ 沙樹に初めて出会ったのは
That yellow cloth looks really nice.
その黄色い布 すてきだね えっ？
Huh?
You're much cooler than the rumors make you out to be, Kida Masaomi.
噂に聞いてたより ずっと かっこいいね 紀田正臣君
What?
何？ なんでオレの名前 知ってんの？
How do you know my name?
Do you have ESP?
エスパー？ むしろ エスパー伊東？
Are you Itou the ESP user?
If you really can read people's minds like that, I'm going
to put you in my bag and take you home with me!
そんな 人の心 読むようなまねしてっと
バッグに詰めて お持ち帰りしちゃうよ～ はい～
Oh, you... That's just too weird!
やだ もう 変なこと 言い過ぎ！
But, it's not me. Someone else has ESP.
でもね 私じゃないよ
エスパーさんは ちゃんと ほかにいるの
Eh? Who is it?
へえ～ 誰よ？
There's a girl with ESP here?
誰か霊感少女がここにいんの？
Anyway, he's an amazing person.
っていうか すごい人なんだよ なんでも知ってるんだから
He knows everything.
It was also the time...I met someone I didn't want to.
会いたくないヤツに 初めて会ったのも そのときだった
Hey, nice to meet you. You're Kida Masaomi, right?
やあ はじめまして
えっと～ 紀田正臣君だよね？
And who might you be?
どちらさんっすか？
I'm Orihara Izaya, an information dealer.
オレは折原臨也 情報屋ってやつさ
This girl's something like my disciple.
まあ この子の後見人みたいなもんだよ
ああ 彼氏とか そういうんじゃないから 安心していいよ
I'm not her boyfriend or anything, so don't worry.
I hope we get along.
よろしく
Shogun!
将軍！
I told you to just call me Kida Masaomi, not "shogun."
言ってんだろ 将軍じゃなくて 紀田正臣でいいってよ
B-But, "Kida" still sounds kind of...
で… でも 紀田さんってのも なんか…
We don't know anything about the Dollars.
ダラーズのことは どうしても分かりません
We have some members who used to be a part
of them, but no one knows who's at the top.
うちの内部にもメンバーだったヤツがいますが
トップのヤツは 分からないそうです
They couldn't identify who it was during
their first gathering six months ago...
半年前の初集会でも 特定できなかったとか
Are they planning on making a move?
なんか 動きはねぇのか？
Apparently their leader issued a statement
saying he wanted information on the Slasher.
リーダーから斬り裂き魔についての情報を求めるって 指令が出たそうです
So, I guess it wasn't true that the Slasher is part of the Dollars.
斬り裂き魔がダラーズだってのは ガセなんですかね？
Even so, something about this is definitely fishy.
そうだとしても 臭いのは間違いねぇだろ
はあ…
Anything else?
ほかには？
Well, Horada got attacked by the black biker, but...
法螺田さんが黒バイクのヤツにやられたって話がありますが…
Who's Horada?
法螺田さん？
It was a while ago, but the black biker attacked us while we
were making fun of some weird guy for wearing a white gas mask...
ちょっと前ですけど
白いガスマスクの変な野郎がいたんで
からかってたら 黒バイクにやられまして…
The black biker...?
黒バイク？
Yeah, it was covered with something
that looked like black oil or whatnot...
はい なんか黒い油みたいなもんにまとわりつかれたっつうか なんつうか…
Just who is this black biker...?
黒バイクって 本当は何者なんだろうな？
There's a rumor that it's involved with the Dollars...
ダラーズの一員だって噂ですが…
Well, whatever...
まあ いいや
By the way, you guys are older than us, aren't you?
ところで あんたら オレらより年上だよな？
ええ まあ…
Y-Yeah, well...
Don't drag in any more adults.
それ以上 年上の連中を引きずり込まないでくれよ
We're done for once we have people's names
getting out like Mr. Whoever from Whatever Group.
なんとか組のなんとかさんなんて 人たちの名前が出てくるようになったら
そのときは 終わりだからな
はあ…
We're just little brats!
オレたちはガキだ
No matter how many of us there are, we can't win
against adults, and we're done for if we get used by them!
いくら人数がいようが 大人の力にゃ勝てないし
利用されるだけされて 終わりだ！
Just like...Orihara Izaya used me...
オレが折原臨也にそうされたみたいにな
Stop it!
やめろ！ おい！
Hey!
Whenever I was even the least bit troubled,
Saki would always say, "Just ask Izaya."
沙樹はオレが少しでも迷うことがあれば
臨也さんに聞けば大丈夫だよ と言った
We'd ask for his opinion on certain things.
何かにつけて 彼の意見を持ち出した
I made it so that you both benefit...
Everyone thought he was annoying at first, but
things actually went well when we did what he said.
みんな 最初はうっとうしく思っていたけれど
実際 そのとおりにすれば いろいろなことがうまくいった
I didn't believe him.
オレは ヤツを信じなかった
I figured I wouldn't get any closer to him than need be.
必要以上に近づこうとは思わなかった
Izaya's really amazing.
臨也さんはほんとにすごいの
He knows everything and he's never wrong.
なんでも分かってるし 絶対に間違えないの
So, would you die if he told you to?
じゃあ ヤツが死ねっつったら 死ぬの？
Probably...
たぶんね…
I took pity on her.
かわいそうな子なんだな と思った
I wanted to release her from Izaya's bonds.
彼女を臨也という男の呪縛から解放してあげたいと思った
I wonder if we can say that we're dating?
オレたちってさ つきあってるって言えんのかな？
I wonder...
どうだろうね？
So, why do you hang out with me?
お前はさ なんで オレなんかと一緒にいんのよ？
ん～ 好きだからだよ
Because I like you.
Did that Izaya guy tell you to like me or something?
あの臨也ってヤツがオレを好きになれとでも言ったのかよ？
Yeah. Only at first, though.
うん 最初だけね
Izaya doesn't interfere with people's love lives.
臨也さんは人の恋愛には口出さないもん
So, why do you still like me?
なんで 今でもオレのこと好きなんだよ？
Because you're cool.
かっこいいから
No, maybe it's because you're cute?
ん～ いや かわいいからかな
What about you?
正臣は？ 私のこと 好き？
Do you like me?
I guess I'd like you if you stopped your zealous devotion to that guy.
ヤツへの狂信的な態度をやめたら 好きになってもいいかな～
I can't help that.
しょうがないよ 欠点の一つぐらい 目をつぶってくれると うれしいな
It'd be nice if you'd overlook at least one of my faults.
You know your own faults?
自分で欠点って 分かってんのかよ
I guess.
まあね 直すつもりないけど
Although I don't plan on fixing them.
If you have a fault, you should fix it.
欠点なら直せよ オレも手伝ってやるからさ
I'll even help you.
And so, we started dating.
そうして オレたちはつきあいはじめた
When I was dating Saki, there was no one to keep me in check.
オレが沙樹とつきあうことをとがめる人間はいなかった
I was serious, and the Yellow Scarves were even
more serious when it came to fighting the Blue Squares.
オレは本気だったし
黄巾賊はブルースクウェアとの抗争で それどころではなかった
They fought dirty.
ヤツらのケンカのしかたは汚かった
They'd attack small groups with large ones,
and they'd lay traps so they could win fights.
少人数を大人数で襲ってくる 勝てるケンカしか仕掛けてこない
They injured over one hundred of my compatriots.
１００人以上の仲間たちがやられた
Everyone was scared.
みんな 怖がっていた オレもだ
And so was I.
I was scared that I'd have to disband the Yellow
Scarves and lose my sense of belonging.
黄巾賊を解散し 居場所がなくなってしまうことが 怖かった
So...
だから…
You should ask Izaya about it.
臨也さんに相談するといいよ
I relied on someone.
オレは頼ってしまったのだ
On him...out of fear...
恐ろしさのあまり あの男を
Welcome!
ようこそ！
I kept telling myself it was for my friends' sakes.
仲間のためだと 自分を納得させて…
Let's take our time talking about it.
まあ ゆっくり話そうじゃないか
His information changed the Yellow Scarves drastically.
ヤツの情報は黄巾賊を劇的に変えた
It wasn't just information about the Blue Squares...
ブルースクウェアの情報だけじゃなく 具体的な戦い方まで 提示してくれた
He even gave us specific information on how to fight.
Our position as the weaker party was quickly reversed.
劣勢だったオレたちの立場は簡単に逆転した
Izaya, you truly are amazing!
At some point, I'd lost my apprehension about him.
オレはいつの間にか この男に対する危機感を失っていた
Moreover, we were winning...
それどころか 勝てる…
I enjoyed our victories.
オレは勝利を楽しんでいた
But...
けれど…
Kiiiiida Masaomi?
紀田～正臣く～ん？
Who's this?
誰だ？
It is nice to meet you.
はじめまして～ ブルースクウェアのトップの泉井君で～す
I'm Izumii, the leader of the Blue Squares!
We're holding a trivia tournament today!
今日はクイズ大会で～す！
Question one: we've asked a special guest to join us; whoever could it be?
第１問 こちらに特別ゲストを呼んでま～す
それは誰でしょうか～？
Here's a hint; this person's very, very, very, very important to you!
ヒント 君のとってもとっても とってもとっても大事な人で～す
Hey!
おい！
Time's up! Or so I'd like to say, but an image
of someone flitted across your mind, didn't it?
ブブ～！ 時間切れ…
と言いたいとこだけど
あんた 今 心の中で一人思い浮かべちゃったりした？
Then bingo, bingo, bingo, bingo!
じゃあ ピンポン ピンポン ピンポ～ンですよぉ！
What have you... What have you done with Saki?!
てめぇ 沙樹を… 沙樹をどうした!?
Question two: What could your precious
girlfriend possibly look like at this moment?
では 第２問で～す
君の大事な彼女は今どんな格好になっているでしょうか～？
Question three:
第３問！
That was the sound of what bone breaking?
今のは どこの骨が折れた音でしょう？
Here's a hint: I don't think she'll be walking any time soon!
ヒント… 彼女はしばらく歩けないと思いま～す
Last question: If you don't come to the parking garage
where you trapped us last time within the next 20 minutes,
最終問題で～す てめぇがあと２０分以内に
こないだオレらをはめた立体駐車場まで来なければ
what in the world will become of this girl?
この女の子は一体どうなってしまうんでしょうか!?
I regretted it.
後悔していた
I'd been naïve.
甘えていたんだ
No matter if I said, "We were still middle schoolers,"
なんだかんだ言っても 自分たちは中学生だと
Or, "This is just the continuation of a backyard brawl,"
子供のケンカの延長だと
It wasn't.
そうじゃなかった これは戦争だ
This was war.
Moreover, I was the one who started it.
しかも それを起こしたのは 自分なんだ
Pick up!
出ろよ… 出てくれよ…
Please, pick up...
The person you have dialed—
ただいま電話に…
What the hell?! Damn it!
何なんだよ ちくしょう！
Izumii, the girl passed out.
泉井さん この女 気絶しちゃいましたよ
How boring.
つまんねぇの まだ足何か所か折っただけじゃんかよ
We just broke one of her bones in a couple of places...
I ran.
オレは走った 行くしかない
All I could do was go there.
行って 沙樹にあんな悲鳴を上げさせたヤツらを 全員殺してやる！
I'd go there...and kill everyone who made Saki scream like that!
The person...
ただいま…
That's why we're going to knock the
leader of the Yellow Scarves down a notch.
だから 黄巾賊… あれのリーダーをぶっちめようって話なんですよ
I told you I'm not taking part in this.
オレは気乗りしねぇっつってんだろ
C'mon now, I heard we kidnapped his girlfriend.
いや あいつの彼女をさらったらしいんですわ
She's just a kid, but she's still pretty womanly!
ガキだけど 結構 いい女っすよ
You can have some fun with that, right?
それだけで十分楽しめるっしょ？
You kidnapped her?
さらった？
Alright, I'll head out right now.
そうか なら 今すぐ行くわ
I knew it! I knew this—
でしょ～？ やっぱ ここは…
Tell this to Izumii when you wake up:
目ぇ覚めたら 泉井のヤツに言っとけ
"So long, you bastard."
あばよ クソ野郎ってな
I couldn't move anymore.
動けなくなった
What I'd felt earlier had just disappeared.
さっきまでの気持ちなんて 消えてしまって
Why did my feet freeze in place...even
though I knew Saki was in danger?
なんで 沙樹がやばいってのに
オレは 足がすくんでるんだよ…
Why...?
なんで… なんで こんなに怖いんだよ
Why am I so scared?
I thought I could do anything if it were for Saki's sake...!
沙樹のためなら なんでもしてやろうと思ってたのに！
I was a powerless...middle schooler.
オレは 非力な ただの中学生だった
Won't she die at this rate?
つうか このままだと 死ぬんじゃねぇっすか？
Not like we care, though.
別に いいっすけど
She's not bleeding, so she should be fine.
血は出てねぇから 大丈夫なんじゃね？
Hello!
どうも～っす！
Well, well, well—
いやいやいや うわっ マジで さらってきちゃってるんっすね
Whoa, so you really did kidnap her!
Oh, it's just you, Yumasaki? Where's Kadota?
なんだ 遊馬崎かよ
門田はどうした？
In reality, this girl would end up in
pieces, unlike in the movies or manga.
こうして 現実では映画や漫画のように助けが来ることなく 女の子はめちゃくちゃにされちゃうんでした
That got me thinking.
だから オレは思うんっすよ
Huh?
I believe that if a hero were to appear and save
her, just maybe the world would turn into 2D,
ここで 彼女を助けるヒーローが現れたら
もしかしたら この世界は二次元になって
and I'd become a superpower-wielding world savior,
オレってば 超能力とか使える 異世界の救世主になって
and I'd be all over the girls like, "Oh my,
tee hee," and, "honk honk, heh heh heh."
女の子たちと キャッキャイヒヒで ムニムニウフフなことになると信じて
And so, to realize my dream, here we go!
夢に向かって ヒアウィゴー！
He's still as weird as ever.
相変わらず キメェ野郎だな
And so, it's time to implement my "let's turn reality
into a happy ending for a 2D heroic story" plan!
というわけで 現実をハッピーエンド式ヒーロー物の二次元世界にしちゃおう計画
発動っす バンザ～イ！
Hurry!
急げ！
Kadota, you asshole!
門田！ てめぇら～！
We probably shouldn't move her too much.
あんまり動かさない方がいいね
We should get her to a hospital fast.
すぐに病院に運んだ方がいいよ
Are you two really okay with this?
お前ら 本当にこれでいいのか？
We follow you, Kadota, so we won't have any
lingering attachments to the Blue Squares.
オレら 門田さんについてってんっすから
ブルースクウェアには未練はないっすよ
Honestly, I'm not good at dealing
with people like Izumii and Horada.
正直 泉井とか法螺田とか ほんと苦手だったんだよね
They're always like, "I second that."
右に同じだよ～っと
It would've been cooler if you'd thrown it out the window.
窓から捨てれば かっこいいのに
I don't like littering.
オレは街は汚さない主義なんだよ
Saki finally woke up.
沙樹はやがて目を覚ました
Thanks to her testimony, Izumii was arrested, and
the weakened Blue Squares were forced to disband.
その証言によって リーダーの泉井は逮捕され
弱体化したブルースクウェアは 強制的に解散に追い込まれた
Hey.
Huh?
You're Kida from the Yellow Scarves, right?
お前 黄巾賊の紀田だろ？
Um, who are you...?
あの… あなたたちは？
How should I explain...
なんて説明したもんかな
My name's Kadota.
オレは門田ってんだけどよ
Ah, I just heard that you betrayed your gang to save Saki.
あんたたちが仲間を裏切って 沙樹を助けてくれたって 聞きました
Um...thank you very much.
あの… ありがとうございました
Well, we're on our way back from visiting her,
but she said you haven't come to her room yet?
いや あの子を見舞ってきた帰りなんだけどよ
お前 まだ行ってないんだって？
That's none of your concern, is it?
あなたたちには関係ないじゃないですか
She asked us to tell you something.
言づてを頼まれた
She can see this whole area from her room.
あの子の病室からだと この辺は丸見えなんだよ
She says, "Thanks for always coming to visit me."
「いつも来てくれて ありがとう」 だとよ
I told her that you were held up by the
Blue Squares and got there a little too late.
あの子には お前は途中で ブルースクウェアの連中に囲まれて
ぎりぎり間に合わなかった そう伝えてある
She wasn't mad at you or anything.
彼女はお前を憎んだりはしてなかったぜ じゃあな
See you.
Why...?
なんで… なんで そんなこと言ったんだよ…
Why did you tell her that?
When did I ever tell you to do that?!
そんなこと オレがいつ頼んだ！
I would've told her the same thing even if you'd said not to.
やめろって頼まれても オレは彼女にそう伝えただろうぜ
You know, don't you?!
分かってるんだろ！ オレは… オレは逃げたんだ
That I...ran away...
My legs froze up...and I couldn't move...
足がすくんで 動けなかったんだ
Yeah, I know.
ああ 知ってる
By the way, you're still running from her.
ついでに言うなら 今もあの子から逃げてるしな
Are you telling me...to lie to her?!
オレにそんな彼女をだませっていうのかよ！
Even though I abandoned her and ran away?!
ほんとは彼女を見捨てて逃げた オレに！
Hey, don't get carried away.
おい 調子に乗んなよ
If you remember the guilt you felt at running away,
逃げたことに罪悪感を覚えてんなら
then at least bear the discomfort that comes
with lying to her for the rest of your life.
一生うそをついてるって 気まずさぐらい背負い続けろ
That'll be your atonement.
それが 彼女にしてやれる 償いだろうがよ
If you still don't want to lie to her,
then face her head on and don't run away!
それでも あの子にうそはつきたくねぇってんなら
逃げねぇで ちゃんと向き合って 言ってやれ
I'll forgive you for running from your past.
過去から逃げるのは許してやる
However...
だけどな
At least don't run from the present or the future!
せめて今と明日からは逃げんじゃねぇよ！
Oh? Did you just say something cool, Kadota?
あれ～？ なんか門田さんがかっこいいこと言ってる
That was awesome! I'm going to
call you Poey the poet from now on...
すっご～い！ これからドタチンのことポエマーポエたんって…
In the end, I just couldn't do it.
結局 オレは行けなかった
I tried. I went there numerous times...
行こうとした 何度も足を運んだ
To simply tell her, "Let's break up."
ただ ひと言 別れようと告げるために
But I couldn't do it.
でも できなかった オレは黄巾賊を離れた
I left the Yellow Scarves.
Have you already decided on a high school, Kida?
紀田君はもう高校とか決めてるの？
I'm going to take the exams for Raira Academy, since it's close.
オレは来良学園を受ける 近いしな
I kept typing words in praise of Raira Academy.
オレは来良を賛美する言葉を打ち込み続けた
I was lonely.
さみしかったんだ
When I talked to Mikado, I felt at ease.
帝人と話すと 心が落ち着いた
You should...
Come too.
And so, I reunited with Mikado.
そして オレは帝人と再会した 杏里とも出会った
I also met Anri.
I thought that my peaceful life as a high schooler would continue.
このまま平穏な高校生活が続くんだと思っていた
And yet...
なのに…
Damn it!
くそっ！ オレを… オレをここに引き戻しやがって
You...You dragged me back into this.
I had absolutely no intention of returning.
決して戻るつもりはなかった
You can't run from her anymore.
君はもう彼女から逃げられないよ
Your feelings of guilt towards her will become
your past, and she'll become a deity to you.
彼女への罪悪感は過去となり
彼女は君にとっての神になる
He was right.
そのとおりだ だから オレはここにいる
That's why I'm here.
I'll defeat the Slasher, who hurt Anri and my friends.
杏里を… 仲間を傷つけた 斬り裂き魔を倒す
I'll defeat the Dollars if the Slasher's with them.
斬り裂き魔がダラーズなら ダラーズも倒す
I won't freeze up any longer.
オレは もう立ちすくまない
This time, I'll definitely...
今度こそ きっと 必ず…
Who's there?!
誰だ!?
What's wrong?
どうした？
A girl was spying on us!
中をのぞいてる女がいたんです 今 追わせてます
Someone's chasing her as we speak!
A girl?
女？
Maybe she's with the Dollars!
ダラーズですかね？
I want to talk with her. Don't be too rough with her.
話が聞きたい 穏便に捕まえろ
Yes, sir!
はい！
I'll go this way!
オレはこっちから回る
I shouldn't have been hesitant at all...
そこに迷いはないはずなのに だから戻ってきた
That's why I returned. That's it...
それだけなのに…
Yet, why...
なのに どうして… どうして こんなにオレの中に不安が響いているんだ？
Why is anxiety rippling throughout my body?
Why...?
どうして？ どうして… どうして 紀田君が…
Why...is Kida...?
The girl runs.
少女は走る ひたすら走る
She runs as fast as she can...
...to escape the shadow that's chasing her,
ただ 追いすがる影から逃れるために
to escape the horrible truth she's discovered.
彼女が知った あまりにも残酷な真実から逃れるために
Next Time: The Blue Dynasty is Dead.
制作：lastzzz akira 安静の云 アキラ
漫游字幕组
http://popgo.net/bbs